Finding Aid for Thomas L. Hankinson papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Thomas L. Hankinson Papers 1899-1935
Hankinson, Thomas Leroy, 1876-1935
(in 10 boxes)
8 linear feet
851398 Aa 2
Naturalist, professor of zoology and physiology at Eastern Illinois State Normal College and Michigan State Normal College, and researcher for state conservation departments in Michigan and Ohio. Correspondence, reports, and field and laboratory notes concerning his studies of the fish of Michigan, Illinois and New York; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated in 1973 by the University Museums (Donor No. 837 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Thomas L. Hankinson was born April 12, 1876, and died December 3, 1935.
T. L. Hankinson was professor of zoology and physiology at Eastern Illinois State Normal College from 1902-1919 and professor of zoology at Michigan State Normal College from 1921-1935. From 1919-1921 he was an ichthyologist at the Roosevelt Wildlife Experimental Station in New York. At the time of his death he also served as a research associate at the University of Michigan. His summer research and investigations were varied: Michigan Biological and Geological Society, 1906, 1913, 1915-1919; New York State College of Forestry, 1915-1919; North Dakota, 1922; Department of Conservation (Michigan), 1923-1925; and the Ohio Bureau of Scientific Research, Division of Conservation, 1930.
Professor Hankinson received his B.S. degree from Michigan Agricultural College (East Lansing, Michigan) in 1898 and a second B.S. from Cornell University in 1900. He was an active member of the Michigan Audubon Society, the American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists, Ecological Society, and the Fisheries Society.
Hankinson's papers are contained in five boxes. Types of materials in the collection include correspondence; topical files on fish studies from Michigan, Illinois, and New York; materials on the Michigan Audubon Society; and field notes (loose leaf, bound volumes, and card files). The time period of these materials ranges from 1899 to 1935.
The archives at Eastern Michigan University in Ypsilanti, Michigan has additional papers of Professor Hankinson.
Subjects:
Hankinson, Thomas L. (Thomas Leroy), 1876-; Conservation of natural resources--United States.; Michigan State Normal College.; Fishes--United States.; Illinois.; Natural resources.; New York (State)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Birds.; Children.; Chippewa County (Mich.); Douglas Lake (Mich.); Hankinson, Thomas Leroy, 1876-1937.; Hankinson family.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Lakes.; New York (State); North Dakota.; Ohio.; Photographs.; Picnics.; Rivers.; Shelldrake (Mich.); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Vermilion (Mich.); Washtenaw County (Mich.); Whitefish Point (Mich.)
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous 1905-1930 (Box 1)
  - Kendall, W.C. 1917-1920 (Box 1)
  - Reighard, Jacob 1915-1921 (Box 1)
  - Ruthven, Alexander 1914-1925 (Box 1)
  - re. Whitefish Point 1913-1915 (Box 1)
- Reports
  - Notes on Illinois fish undated (Box 1)
  - Fish in streams about Charleston, Illinois undated (Box 1)
  - Michigan Fish Investigation 1916 (Box 1)
  - Allegany State Park Fish 1921 (Box 1)
  - Lake Erie Fish Survey circa 1930 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Audubon Society (Box 1)
- Field and Lab Notes (loose leaf)
  - Whitfefish Point Field and Lab Notes (Box 1)
  - Field and lab notes, New York, with Photographs 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - New York Fish-other than Oneida Lake, Palisades Park 1918-19 (including plants and animals), Co-operative Ecological survey Mount Marey Hamilton Co., New York; Oneida Lake, New York; Erie and Niagara Co., New York; Allegany Park-1920 (Box 1)
  - North Dakota Fish.-Field and Lab Notes-1922 (Box 1)
  - Field Notes mainly New York, some Michigan and Ohio 1928 (Box 1)
  - Field Notes on Birds, Charleston, Illinois (Box 1)
  - Summary of Field and Lab Notes (Box 1)
  - Kickapoo Creek, Charleston, Illinois 1905-1911 (Box 1)
  - Oneida Lake, New York 1916 (Box 1)
  - Palisades Park 1918 (Box 1)
  - Western New York 1920 (Box 1)
  - Great Lakes Region 1921-1923 (Box 1)
  - North Dakota 1922 (Box 2)
  - Oneida Lake 1927 (Box 2)
- Field and Lab Notes (bound volumes)
  - Volume 1: July 1899-July 1900 Ithaca, New York (Box 2)
  - Volume 2: July 1900-April 1901 Ithaca, New York (Box 2)
  - Volume 3: April 1901-February 1902 Ithaca, New York (Box 2)
  - Volume 4: March 1902-June 1902 Ithaca, New York (Box 2)
  - Volume 5: June-August 1920 Ithaca, New York (Box 2)
  - Volume 5: August-September 1902 Ohio and Michigan (Box 2)
  - Volume 5: August 1903 Clark, Indiana (Box 2)
  - Volume 5: March-April 1904 Charleston, Illinois (Box 2)
  - Volume 6: January-August 1905 Charleston, Illinois (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous topical files (unprocessed)
  - Miscellaneous topical files (unprocessed) (Box 2)
- Field and Lab Notes (card files)
  - Station notes, including photographs, Oakland County, Michigan April-June 1906 (Box 3)
    (loose card file)
  - Station Notes, Champlain, Illinois 1906-1910 (Box 3)
    (boxed card file)
- Field and Lab Notes (card files)
  - Charleston, Illinois 1906-1910, 1911-1921 (Box 4)
  - Field Notes, Including Summer Work, New York 1916 (Box 4)
  - Central New York 1920-1921; Station Notes, Charleston, Illinois, 1914-1917 (Box 4)
  - Station Notes, including photographs, Charleston, Illinois 1907-1918 (Box 4)
  - Field Notes, Michigan (Box 5)
  - Station notes, Central Illinois 1911-1913 (Box 5)
  - Breeding Illinois Fish, including photographs, prior to 1922 (Box 5)
- Photographs
  - Prints (Box 6)
  - Place file
    - Boyne, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Calhoun County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - California (Box 6)
    - Detroit Zoo (Box 6)
    - Douglas Lake, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Hillsdale County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Huron River and tributaries (Box 6)
    - Illinois (Box 6)
    - Jack Miner's, Kingsville, Ontario (Box 6)
    - Kalamazoo County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Lenawee County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Michigan (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Monroe County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - New York (Box 6)
    - North Dakota (Box 6)
    - Ohio (Box 6)
    - Van Buren County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Vermilion and Shelldrake, Michigan (Box 6)
    - Washtenaw County, Michigan
      - General (Box 6)
      - Lakes (Box 6)
    - Wayne County, Michigan (Box 6)
    - The West (Box 6)
  - Subject file (place unidentified)
    - Amphibians and reptiles (Box 6)
    - Birds
      - General (Box 6)
      - Habitats (Box 6)
      - Nests (Box 6)
      - Winter feeding (Box 6)
    - Dogs (Box 6)
    - Fish (Box 6)
    - Friends and relatives (unidentified) (Box 6)
    - Hankinson, Janet
      - Alone (Box 6)
      - With other children (Box 6)
    - Hankinson, T.L.
      - Alone (Box 6)
      - Family groups (Box 6)
    - Houses (Box 6)
    - Insects (Box 6)
    - Lakes (Box 6)
    - Mammals (Box 6)
    - Michigan State Normal College field trip (Box 6)
    - Night herons (Box 6)
    - Picnics (Box 6)
    - Plants and insects (Box 6)
    - Sand dunes (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (unidentified) (Box 6)
  - Negatives (Staff use only-Glass)
    The descriptions, with few exceptions were transcribed as written from the negative sleeves.
    - 1906-July 1913 (Box 7)
      - 1906
        (Note: From April 16, 1906 through August 28, 1906 photographs were taken at Walnut Lake, Oakland Co., Michigan or other localities when indicated.)
        - April 16, Station 1. Looking west from lake (Box 7)
        - April 16, Station 4a. Shore and stony bottom. No.82 (Box 7)
        - April 16, Station 16 (Box 7)
        - May 28, Outlet looking north from turn west of Robertson's. No.60 (Box 7)
        - May 28, Outlet looking south from junction with outlet of Simpson Lake.-No.61 (Box 7)
        - May, Station 40. Central portion. No.95. (Box 7)
        - June 25, Aromochelys[?] oderatus eggs with turtle at Stn.41. 6 Am (Box 7)
        - June 25, Mr. McDonald gathering turtle eggs at Stn.41 from muskrat house. 6 AM (Box 7)
        - July 1, Station 2. Looking west. 12 M. No.161. (Box 7)
        - July 7, Station 20. Looking north, 3:30 PM (Box 7)
        - July 16, Station 1. Looking east and view of lake. 4:45 PM. (Box 7)
        - July,[?], Station 6. Sedge region (Box 7)
        - August 3, Station 26. Looking south. (Box 7)
        - August 8, Lake St. Clair. Showing rush front, New Baltimore (Box 7)
        - August 8, Region where collecting was done, New Baltimore. No.199 (Box 7)
        - August 8, Parke Davis Co. buildings, from Detroit River. No.226 (Box 7)
        - Aug'. 19, McDonald at thermosphere[?]. 5 PM. No.227 (Box 7)
        - Aug. 24, Stn.23. Showing beach with encroaching vegetation. No.215 (Box 7)
        - Aug. 28, Stn.19. 8:30 AM (Box 7)
      - 1907
        (Note: From March 22, 1907 to June 15, 1913 photos were made in Charleston, Coles Co., Illinois or other localities as indicated. Hankinson was at Eastern Illinois State Normal School.)
        - January 27, Snow and ice scene near rocks [Illinois?] (Box 7)
        - March 22, Chorophilus [?] pond (larger) 1/2 mile S. of Normal School (Box 7)
        - May 8, Hodgin's Pond. 4 PM (Box 7)
        - May 8, Hodgin's Pond showing floating algae. 4 P-M (Box 7)
        - May 10, Meandering stream in Happy Valley. 3:30 PM (Box 7)
        - June 15, Ohio River from park, Louisville, Ky. (Box 7)
        - June 15, Port of Louisville, Ky., from steamer on Ohio River circa June 15, 1907 (Box 7)
        - June 24, Kickapoo Creek near mouth. Bay [bog?] in which long-, eared sunfish nests were found. Nest was located in the front of bay in background. View across stream to south. (Box 7)
        - June 24, Kickapoo Creek near mouth. Bay in which long-eared sunfish, nest was found extending [?] to right (Box 7)
        - July 1, View on Indian creek. Place where nests of Primephalis, notatus [?] found. These nests in ripples and in more quiet places about ripples (Box 7)
        - July 4, Kickapoo Creek. Part of stream where Primaphalis notatus nests were found (Box 7)
        - July 8, Leather back turtle Aspi donecter spinifer [?] partly, concealed in sand of stream bottom. Rily [sic] Creek (Box 7)
        - July 23, Indian Creek and party, Indian Creek (Box 7)
        - July 27, Bay at SW corner of Normal School pond showing nesting place of sunfish Leperius megolatus [?] and Leperius cyanellus [?] (Box 7)
        - December 20, Snow scene. Ravine 1 mi. S. of Normal School (Box 7)
        - December 20, Cornfield 1/2 mi. S. of Normal School (Box 7)
      - 1908
        - January 6, Interior of woods N. of dam (Box 7)
        - January 6, Ravine 2 miles SE of Normal School looking west. S tn.84 (Box 7)
        - January 13, Bushy margin of small stream S. of Normal School grounds (Box 7)
        - March 18, Eggs of Amblystoma tigrinum taken 12 M. Eggs from Hodgin's Pond March 6 (Box 7)
        - June 30, N. end of Normal School pond looking W. Stn.1 in foreground (Box 7)
        - September 3, View on Olson [?] River, 2 mi. below Cook's Mills, Ill., looking upstream (Box 7)
      - 1909
        - January 20, Barred owl (Box 7)
        - March 15, Station 23. Leaf Dam at upper end. (A) (Box 7)
        - March 31, Station 22. Looking downstream, showing nesting haunts of Campostoma anormalum [?] in foreground. (I) (Box 7)
        - April 17, Haunts of Campostoma anormalum [?]. Several nests above ripples. See notes for April 18. (A) (Box 7)
        - September 13, Station 57a looking north. (B) (Box 7)
        - October 2, Drainage ditch near Fair Grange, looking N. (A) (Box 7)
        - November 7, Station 20 looking SE. (J) (Box 7)
      - 1910
        - February 22, Stn. 20 a (N) (Box 7)
        - March 23, Stn. 20a. Comprehensive view of nesting habitat of Compostoma anormalum. W (Box 7)
        - March 31, Nesting haunts of Compostoma anormalum. Upper Kickapoo. (A) (Box 7)
        - March 31, Upper Kickapoo. Breeding haunts of Compostoma anormalum and suckers. (C) (Box 7)
        - March 31, Upper Kickapoo. Breeding haunts of Compostoma anormalum and suckers. (D) (Box 7)
        - March 31, Upper Kickapoo Creek. (G) (Box 7)
        - August 9, Station 301f looking NE. (B) (Box 7)
        - August 9, Station 301. North portion, including 301a. (H) (Box 7)
        - August 9, Station 301. Rudbeckia and Silphium patch. Q) (Box 7)
        - August 9, Station 301. (Box 7)
        - 1911 (Box 7)
        - April 23, Station 301f. Looking E from track. (A) (Box 7)
        - April 23, Station 301a. Looking N. (D) (Box 7)
        - August 10, Embarrass EN River near Oakland, Ill. (3) (Box 7)
        - August 12, Salt Fork of Vermilion River, Oakwood, Ill., Looking downstream. (4) (Box 7)
        - August 12, Salt Fork of Vermilion River looking upstream. (5) (Box 7)
        - August 12, Salt Fork of Vermilion River. (6) (Box 7)
        - August 12, Camp at Salt Fork of Vermilion River. (7) (Box 7)
        - August 12, Salt Fork of Vermilion River near Oakwood, Ill. (9) (Box 7)
        - August 14, Embarrass River near Camargo, Ill. (10) (Box 7)
        - August 14, Embarrass River near Camargo, Ill. (13) (Box 7)
        - August 16, Kaskaskia River near Sullivan, Ill., looking downstream. (14) (Box 7)
        - August 16, Kaskaskia River near Sullivan, Ill., looking upstream. (15) (Box 7)
        - August 16, Kaskaskia River near Humboldt, Ill., looking upstream. (16) (Box 7)
        - August 16, Kaskaskia River near Sullivan, Ill., showing very shallow portion of stream. (17) (Box 7)
        - August 18, Mosquito Creek. (18) (Box 7)
        - August 18, Sangamon River N. of Blue Mound, Ill. (20) (Box 7)
        - August 18, Sangamon River N. of Blue Mound, Ill. (22) (Box 7)
        - August 18, Sangamon River near Bolivia, Ill., showing high clay banks and camp. (24) (Box 7)
        - August 18, Sangamon River near Bolivia, Ill., looking upstream. (25) (Box 7)
        - August 21, Sangamon River near Taylorsville, Ill., with our team and wagon near S. fork. (26) (Box 7)
        - August 21, S. fork of Sangamon River near Taylorville, Ill. (28) (Box 7)
        - August 23, Kaskaskia River near Vern, Ill. (31) (Box 7)
        - August 25, South Slough of Kaskaskia River, looking upstream. (32) (Box 7)
        - August 25, Kaskaskia River near Sholsmir [?], Ill., looking downstream. (33) (Box 7)
        - August 28, Little Wabash River near Louisville, Ill., looking upstream. (36) (Box 7)
        - August 29, Muddy Creek near Noble, Ill., looking upstream. (39) (Box 7)
        - August 29, Little Muddy Creek near Sailor Springs, ill. (40) (Box 7)
        - August 30, Embarrass River near West Liberty, Ill., looking upstream (Box 7)
        - August 31, Lans Creek near Inglaham, Ill. (43) (Box 7)
        - September 1, Embarrass River near Newton, Ill, looking downstream, showing region where Lepisostens ossena [?] and Dossena [?] and Ictrolus [?] were common. (44) (Box 7)
        - September 1, Embarrass River near Newton, Ill., looking upstream. (46) (Box 7)
        - September 4, Embarrass River near Greenup, Ill., looking downstream. (47) (Box 7)
        - September 4, Embarrass River near Greenup, Ill., looking upstream. (48) (Box 7)
        - September 4, Cottonwood Creek near Toledo, Ill. (52) (Box 7)
        - September 5, Indian Creek near Lerna, Ill. (54) (Box 7)
        - September 5, Indian Creek near Lerna, Ill. (55) (Box 7)
      - 1912
        - April 20, Station 23. Happy Valley. Looking N. (Box 7)
        - May 7, Station 84. Showing region where Compostoma anormalum [?], was nesting. Nests almost oval[?] on back of plate. (A) (Box 7)
        - May 27, Upper Cassel Creek 1/2 mile W. of Marshalls [I11.]. (I) (Box 7)
        - May 27, Marshall Pond looking W. Largest pond. (A) (Box 7)
        - September 13, Station 301. Roadside vegetation. (E) (Box 7)
        - September 13, Station 301. Cone gall of willow. (D) (Box 7)
      - 1913
        - January 25, Station 18H. Looking NE. (Box 7)
        - March 12, Station 30. Looking easterly (Box 7)
        - March 13, Station 22. Drift material along stream, showing maple seeds (Box 7)
        - March 19, Station 105H. Boulder Pool. (D) (Box 7)
        - March 19, Station 105L. Effects of landslide in stream. (F) (Box 7)
        - March 30, Station 301. General view looking NE (Box 7)
        - March 30, Station 301. Androfagan [?] shoots burned off on higher part of stalk (Box 7)
        - April 5, Station 21 (Box 7)
        - April 5, Station 110 (Box 7)
        - April 7, Station 110. Briar patch showing blackberry stems (Box 7)
        - April 15, Chorophilus [?] pool in field just east of school garden (Box 7)
        - May 1, Region about nesting pool when Semstetin atromaculatum [?] were nesting. Looking easterly downstream. (B) (Box 7)
        - May 18, Station 301. (A) (Box 7)
        - June 15, Station 100. Embarrass [?] River. Looking upstream (Box 7)
          (Note: From this point through August 23, 1913 negative envelopes stamped Whitefish Point, Chippewa Co., Mich.)
        - July 29, Lake and woodland view looking N. (A) (Box 7)
        - July 30, Great blue heron in nest (Box 7)
    - August 1913-June 1919 (Box 8)
      - 1913
        - August 1, West end of North lake[?] of Vermillion Lake (Box 8)
        - August 2, Stump of tree cut down by beaver at northeast[?] corner of John Clark's cranberry marsh showing tooth marks of beaver (Box 8)
        - August 2, Station 59. Looking NE from W. end of station showing character of heath zone (Box 8)
        - August 2, Station 71. Looking W along N shore of lake, called stn-71 (Box 8)
        - August 3, Shelldrake River, looking downstream from E end of the small lake, 2 mi. E of Vermillion (Box 8)
        - August 3, Shelldrake River looking SW (Box 8)
        - August 3, Vermilion Region looking W from top of cranberry shoot VI (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 30. Looking S, upstream from lake beach (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 30. Looking N, downstream (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 101. Lake E. of Vermilion. Looking E (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 101 (foreground) (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 103 (near shore) (Box 8)
        - August 4, Station 106 (far shore) (Box 8)
        - August 6, Vermilion Beach looking SE from pier (Box 8)
        - August 6, Station 116, about 1 mi. E of Vermilion. Looking N showing character of shore (Box 8)
        - August 6, East Vermilion Lake. Looking east from sand bluff. Lake nearest includes stations 101, 103, and 106 (Box 8)
        - August 6, East Vermilion Lake looking E from large sand bluff about 1/2 mi. east of Vermilion. Lake in foreground with stations 101, 103, 106 (Box 8)
        - August 7, Lake a mile SE of Vermilion. Stn.111 in foreground. A deer on shore in background (Box 8)
        - August 7, Hay meadow of Mr. Clark's and lake, including Stn.111, looking NE (Box 8)
        - August 9, Shelldrake Lake Region. General view showing lake in distance (Box 8)
        - August 9, Shelldrake River and surrounding marsh at W. end of Shelldrake Lake looking S. Marsh in foreground. Stn.141. (Box 8)
        - August 9, Shelldrake River a short distance W. of Shelldrake Lake, looking upstream (Box 8)
        - August 9, Station 142. Part of N. shore of Shelldrake Lake looking E. (Box 8)
        - August 11, Station 121. Looking upstream on beach portion of stream (Box 8)
        - August 11, Station 121 looking downstream on beach portion of stream (Box 8)
        - August 13, Station 52 looking SE (Box 8)
        - August 13, Station 55 looking N from lake (Box 8)
        - August 13, Station 84 looking E (Box 8)
        - August 13, Station 85 looking SE (Box 8)
        - August 13, Station 53 looking NW (Box 8)
        - August 14, NE Beach Lake looking SE (Box 8)
        - August 15, Beach Lake looking W (Box 8)
        - August 23, Station 55 looking westerly showing the favorite fish habitat on W. Vermilion Lake (Box 8)
        - August 28, Station 1. Pebbly beach of Lake Superior, Vermilion, Mich., about 300 ft. E. of Station 1 (Box 8)
        - September 1, Rapids at Sault Ste. Marie looking across and upstream (Box 8)
          (Note: From this point through May 2, 1919 negative envelopes again stamped Charleston, Coles Co., Illinois)
        - October 4, Kickapoo Creek looking N (Box 8)
        - October 4, Station 54. Looking N. Showing Lerma [?] and Spiradela [?] covered surface (Box 8)
        - November 24, Station 301. South end (Box 8)
        - November 24, Station 301 looking SE (Box 8)
      - 1914
        - January 16, Station 301 (Box 8)
        - January 16, Station 301 looking N from S end (Box 8)
        - January 16, Station 302 (Box 8)
        - January, Effects of ice storm, Tenth Street, Charleston, Ill. (Box 8)
        - April 13, Roadway near Station 105 (Box 8)
        - April 15, Marshall Ponds (northeast) (Box 8)
        - April 22, Station 19L looking West (Box 8)
        - April 26, Town Branch, close to mouth, looking easterly (Box 8)
        - April 26, Station 64 looking south (Box 8)
        - May 14, Flat Branch 2 miles east of Humboldt, Ill., looking easterly upstream (Box 8)
        - May 16, Stn.135. General view of region just above dam, Embarrass [?] River (Box 8)
        - May 21, Stn. 302 looking south (Box 8)
        - May 21, Stn. 302. Cottomwood Region. Looking east. Flicker's nest in a short strip 1 3/4" from left edge of plate (Box 8)
        - May 24, Dump heap in town branch near 3rd Street (Box 8)
        - June 8, Station 312 looking SE (Box 8)
        - July 6, Young Cooper's Hawks from the Whitstom [?] Ford region (Box 8)
      - 1915
        - March 17, Station 104 looking south from railroad bridge (Box 8)
        - March 31, Station 49. Fish-containing pool. Looking upstream. Lower part of creek (Box 8)
        - April 3, Station 301 (Box 8)
        - April 3, Station 302 (Box 8)
        - April 15, Dice's Woods near Dicker Springs looking downstream at Cossil [?] Creek showing ripples on which Campostoma anormalia [?] are working (Box 8)
        - April 15, Roadway at Dice's Woods, Cossil Creek region near Decker Springs looking north (Box 8)
        - April 18, Wooded ravine. Stn.90. Side ravine of water works ravine (Box 8)
        - May 10, Stn. 102. Polecat Creek Region (Box 8)
        - May 23, Fath [?] Pond near Hillsboro, Ill. and Geffern, Ill. Nesting habitat of King Rail [with] person in picture looking at nest and standing by it (Box 8)
        - June 19, East Big Four [? Bry Farm?] Pond, south end looking east (Box 8)
        - June 19, East Big Four woods looking SE. Stn.105 (Box 8)
        - September 29, Field SW of Wrightville [?] (Box 8)
      - 1916
        - May 16, Young screech owls (Box 8)
        - May 16, Stn.92. Heterodon [?], "flying possum" [snake] (Box 8)
        - May 16, Heterodon, "flying possum" (Box 8)
        - May 16, Stn.92. Heterodon, spreading (Box 8)
      - 1917
        - February 19, Abnormal leopard frog. Preserved specimen. See data on neg. (Box 8)
        - February 19, Abnormal leopard frog. Preserved specimen. See data on neg. (Box 8)
        - February 21, Crotalus horridus [snake], taken September 16, 1916 (Box 8)
        - May 30, Sparrow hawk, about May 30, 1917 (Box 8)
      - 1918
        - March, Pool in field just east of Normal School campus (Box 8)
        - May 18, Station 301 looking east (Box 8)
        - May 19, River Valley road at Walter Ford (Box 8)
        - August 17, Little Long Pond and Kahnawake [?] Lake beyond. (Box 8)
        - August 25, Chestnuts killed by blight near Goust House (Box 8)
        - August, Car Pond (Box 8)
        - August, Kanalwarke Lake (Box 8)
        - August, Island outcrop in Cedar Pond (Box 8)
        - August, Road along Cedar Pond (Box 8)